You thought it was just a story.
Boogeyman is a thriller, horror, drama film directed by Stephen Kay.
Every culture has one – the horrible monster
fueling young children's nightmares.
But for Tim, the Boogeyman still lives in his memories as a
creature that devoured his father 16 years ago.
Is the Boogeyman real, or did Tim make it up to explain
why his father abandoned his family?
Tim, played by Barry Watson.
Kate Houghton, played by Emily Deschanel.
Tim's Mother, played by Lucy Lawless.
Franny Roberts, played by Skye McCole Bartusiak.
Jessica, played by Tory Mussett.
Jessica's Mom, played by Louise Wallace.
Boogeyman is a 2005 supernatural horror film directed by Stephen Kay and starring Barry Watson,
Emily Deschanel, Skye McCole Bartusiak, Tory Mussett, Charles Mesure, and Lucy Lawless.
Written by Eric Kripke, Juliet Snowden, and Stiles White, from a story by Kripke, the film is a new take on
the classic "boogeyman", or monster in the closet, who is the eponymous antagonist of the film.
The plot concerns a young man returns to the house he grew up in to
confront the childhood terror that has affected his life.
It’s an international co-production between the
United States, New Zealand and Germany.
The film was panned by critics, often citing a generic
and unoriginal plot as the main criticism.
Despite receiving negative reviews from critics, it was a financial success and was followed
by two direct-to-video sequels, Boogeyman 2 (2007) and Boogeyman 3 (2008).
The film explores themes of nightmare, hallucination,
childhood trauma, break-up, hometown.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.